Berryman Family
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Berryman family papers
1829-1984, bulk 1882-1961
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Berryman family
11.3 linear feet
The Berryman family papers measure 11.3 linear feet and date from 1829 to 1984, with the bulk of the material dating from 1882 to 1961. The collection presents a good overview of the careers of Washington Star cartoonist Clifford Berryman, his daughter, Star art critic, Florence, and to a lesser extent, son Jim Berryman.
Biographical Note
The patriarch of the Berryman family, Clifford Kennedy Berryman, was born in Versailles, Kentucky, in 1869. His first job was in the U.S. Patent Office in Washington, D.C. He became a cartoonist for the Washington Post in 1891. From 1907, until his death in 1949, Clifford Berryman was political cartoonist for the Washington Star, earning a reputation as the “Dean of American Cartoonist,” and winning a Pulitzer Prize in 1944. His cartoon of Theodore Roosevelt, “Drawing the Line in Mississippi,” 1902, began the American Teddy Bear craze, and created Berryman's cartoon trademark. He was also the first cartoonist to become president of the Gridiron Club. His wife, Kate, was an avid member of the Daughters of the American Revolution.
Their daughter, Florence Berryman, 1900-1992, abandoned her study of music because of a loss of hearing and turned her attention to art. In the 1920s, she became a free-lance local art critic, writing articles for newspapers. She later assisted Leila Mechlin, as an art critic for the Washington Star. In 1946, Florence Berryman succeeded Mechlin and worked for the Star until her retirement in 1961. She also served as editor for the American Federation of Arts until 1944.
Clifford and Kate Berryman's son, James Thomas Berryman, 1902-1976, attended George Washington University and the Corcoran School of Art. He worked as a reporter for the New Mexico State Tribune, until his return, in 1923, to Washington, D.C. because of his mother's illness. He worked at the Washington Star, as an editorial artist and illustrator, until 1933, when he became a sports cartoonist. When his father suffered a storke in 1935, Jim intermittently drew political cartoons for the STAR. Jim Berryman also won a Pulitzer Prize for his political cartoons.
Scope and Content Note
The Berryman family papers measure 11.3 linear feet and date from 1829 to 1984, with the bulk of the material dating from 1882 to 1961. The collection presents a good overview of the careers of Washington Star cartoonist Clifford Berryman, his daughter, Star art critic, Florence, and his son, Jim Berryman, though the latter's career is not as well represented. The papers also contain material relating to Kate Berryman, including a scrapbook and diaries.
The collection contains biographical material, correspondence, business records, notes and writings, scrapbooks, printed material, photographs, and artwork by Clifford and Jim Berryman and others.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into three series according to individual family members; each series is arranged into subseries and material within each subseries is arranged chronologically.
Series 1: Clifford and Kate Berryman papers, 1829-1963, undated (boxes 1-7, 11-12, OVs 14-15, 7.9 linear ft.)
Series 2: Florence Berryman Papers, 1902-1984, undated (boxes 8-10, 13, 2.3 linear ft.)
Series 3: Jim Berryman Papers, 1919-1964, undated (boxes 10, 13, 1.1 linear ft.)
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following index terms:
Subjects:
Bryan, William Jennings, 1860-1925; Coolidge, Calvin, 1872-1933; Daniels, Josephus, 1862-1948; Garner, John Nance, 1868-1967; Harding, Warren G. (Warren Gamaliel), 1865-1923; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964; Putnam, Brenda, 1890-1975; Reynolds, Joseph G., 1886-1972; Rogers, Will, 1879-1935; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919; Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924; Gridiron Club (Washington, D.C.); American Federation of Arts; Society of Washington Artists (Washington, D.C.)
Subjects-Topical:
Cartooning -- Washington (D.C.); Caricatures and cartoons -- Washington (D.C.); Political cartoons -- Washington (D.C.); Politicians -- Caricatures and cartoons; Women art critics -- Washington (D.C.); Art criticism -- Washington (D.C.); Art critics -- Washington (D.C.); Cartoonists -- Washington (D.C.); Politicians -- Washington (D.C.)
Types of Materials:
Works of art; Diaries; Drawings; Illustrated letters; Photographs; Sketchbooks
Names:
McCutcheon, John T. (John Tinney), 1870-1949; Mechlin, Leila, 1874-1949; Baruch, Bernard M. (Bernard Mannes), 1870-1965; Byrd, Harry Flood, 1887-1966; Clay, Henry, 1777-1852; Darling, Jay N. (Jay Norwood), 1876-1962; Debs, Eugene V. (Eugene Victor), 1855-1926; Grosvenor, Gilbert Hovey, 1875-1966; Hays, Will H. (Will Harrison), 1879-1954; Hoover, J. Edgar (John Edgar), 1895-1972; Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1850-1924; Berryman, Clifford Kennedy, 1869-1949; Berryman, Florence Seville, 1900-1992; Berryman, James Thomas, 1902-1971; Berryman, Kate
Provenance
Portions of the Berryman family papers were donated in 1965 by Florence Berryman, and in 1992 by her estate. The latter donation included portions of a scrapbook of memorabilia which had previously been lent for filming (reel D111) by Florence Berryman in 1962. The whearabouts of the other items in the scrapbook which were donated is unknown.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Patrons must use microfilm copy.
Alternative Forms Available
The collection is available on microfilm reels D111 and 4767-4776. The microfilm is available for interlibrary loan.
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Clifford and Kate Berryman Papers, 1829-1963, undated, Series 1:; (boxes 1-7, sols 11-12, OVs 14-15, 7.9 linear ft.)
  This series is arranged into ten subseries:
  1.1: Biographical Material, 1847-1961
  1.2: Diaries, 1928-1948
  1.3: Correspondence, 1829-1953, undated
  1.4: Business Records, 1874-1937
  1.5: Notes, 1940-1963, undated
  1.6: Writings, 1944-1946, undated
  1.7: Artwork, circa 1882-1945, undated
  1.8: Scrapbooks, 1902-1945
  1.9: Printed Material, 1856-1972, undated
  1.10: Photographs, 1892-1949, undated
  - Biographical Material, 1847-1961, 1.1:
    Material found here includes 25 of Clifford's identity cards and a scrapbook of Kate's genealogical research material, including notes, letters, clippings, and photographs.
    - Clifford Berryman's identity cards, 1906-1950 (Box 1, Reel 4767)
    - Scrapbook of Kate Berryman's genealogical research, 1847-1961, (5 folders) (Box 1, Reel 4767)
  - Diaries, 1928-1948, 1.2:
    These diaries were written primarily by Kate Berryman, with a few entries in the 1928 volume written by Clifford.
    - Diaries, 1928-1931, 1936 (Box 1, Reel 4767)
    - Diaries, 1936, 1940-1941, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Reel 4768)
  - Correspondence, 1829-1953, undated, 1.3:
    This series includes a scrapbook of greeting cards to family members illustrated by Clifford and Jim Berryman, but primarily contains letters written by presidents, notable politicians, and other political cartoonists, discussing Clifford Berryman's work.
    See index for List of Notable Correspondents from 1.3: Correspondence
    Index
    Notable Correspondents from 1.3: Correspondence
    Adams, Alva B. (Senator, Colorado): 18 Oct 1938, 05 Apr 1941
    Akerson, George (Secretary to the President): 10 Jul 1929
    Albright, Horace M. (Director, National Park Service): 02 Dec 1932
    Alexander, D. (Congressman): undated
    Allen, Henry J. (Senator, Kansas): May 13, 1930
    Allison, William B. (Senator, Iowa): 03 Jun 1906
    Alston, Frank H., Jr. (artist): 22 Jul 1947
    Anderson, Clint (Sec. of Agriculture): 13 Sep 1945
    Andrews, Marietta (illustrator): undated, 05 Feb 1925 (illustrated letter), 16 Sep 1928 (illustrated letter), Jan 1930
    Arnold, Oren (writer): 04 Mar 1944
    Ashurst, Henry F. (Senator, Arizona): 11 Feb 1941
    Astor, Vincent: undated (letter from C. Berryman), 11 Nov 1932, 12 Nov 1932 (letter from C. Berryman), 14 Nov 1932, 17 Nov 1932, 12 Apr 1933
    Auchincloss, James C. (Congressman, New Jersey): 12 Nov 1947
    Austin, Warren R. (Senator, Vermont): 24 Oct 1941, 28 Oct 1941, 29 Oct 1941 (letter from Mrs. Austin)
    Babcock, J. W. (Congressman, Wisconsin): 12 Jun 1903
    Bailey, Josiah William (Senator, North Carolina): 26 Jan 1938, 14 July 1938, 21 Jun 1939, 26 Jun 1939
    Baird, G. W. (cartoonist?): 20 Jul 1914?
    Baker, James M. (Senator): 05 Aug 1916
    Baker, Newton D. (Secretary of War): 10 Mar 1916, 08 Jan 1917, 10 Feb 1920, 27 Mar 1920, 06 Apr 1920
    Baldwin, Stanley (Prime Minister): 19 Apr 1929 (letter about him)
    Ballinger, Richard A. (Secretary of the Interior): 08 Mar 1909, 23 Sep 1911, 08 Apr 1916
    Barclay: undated (illustrated letter)
    Barkley, Alben W. (Senator, Kentucky): 19 Feb 1943, 01 Dec 1943
    Barrett, John (Director, Pan American Union): 06 Mar 1915
    Barrett, Robert (Evening World): 07 Oct 1927
    Bartlett, John H. (Asst. Postmaster General and Governor of New Hampshire): 02 Apr 1924, 11 Nov 1927, 30 Jul 1932, 15 Dec 1949
    Baruch, Bernard M.: 09 Mar 1938, 16 Sep 1943
    Bassford, Wallace (secretary of Speaker's Room, House of Representatives): 12 Dec 1913
    Bastedo, P. H. (Rear Admiral): 09 May 1947
    Beckham, J. Crepps Wickliffe (Senator, Kentucky): 07 Mar 1916, 29 Mar 1916, 20 Dec 1919
    Berger, Victor L. (Congressman, Wisc.): 05 Feb 1924
    Beveridge, Albert J. (Senator, Indiana): 21 Feb 1907, 30 Mar 1907, 18 May 1935
    Biddle, Francis (Attorney General): 09 Jan 1942, 23 Mar 1942, 20 Apr 1942, 08 May 1942, 25 May 1942, 09 Jun 1942
    Bittinger, Charles: 30 Nov 1931, 13 Feb 1938
    Blackburn, J. C. S. (Senator): 09 Jan 1906
    Bland, Schuyler Otis (Congressman, Va.): 30 Dec 1941
    Bliss, Edward Goring: 21 Feb 1936
    Bloom, Sol (Congressman, New York): 09 Apr 1928, 26 Apr 1928, 05 May 1931, 19 Feb 1932, 07 May 1932, 09 Mar 1933, 22 Oct 1934, 09 Nov 1934, 21 May 1935, 07 Mar 1936, 26 Mar 1936, 08 Jun 1936, 31 Aug 1936, 15 Dec 1936, 03 Jan 1938, 10 Jun 1940, 18 Jan 1941, 10 Mar 1941
    Boardman, Mabel: 14 Apr 1912
    Bolton, Frances P. (Congresswoman, Ohio): 05 Mar 1942
    Bone, Homer T. (Senator, Washington): 19 Apr 1944
    Bone, Scott C. (editor, The Washington Herald and the Post-Intelligencier): 27 Jan 1908, 05 Oct 5 1911
    Bone, Scott W. (son of Scott C. Bone): 10 Oct 1932
    Borah, William E. (Senator): 03 Oct 1921 (letter about him)
    Brayman, Harold (President, National Press Club): 07 Mar 1938, 03 May 1944
    Bridges, H. Styles (Senator, N. H.): 28 Feb 1938
    Britten, Fred A. (Congressman, Illinois): 25 Dec 1934
    Brooke, Frederick (architect): undated, 12 May 1945
    Browne, Edward E. (Congressman, Wisc.): 17 Feb 1931
    Bruker, John (Governor, Ohio): 21 Feb 1944
    Bryan, William Jennings: undated, 09 Dec 1907, 19 Jan 1908, 16 Jan 16 1913, 15 Aug 1914, 24 Feb 1915, 02 Mar 1915 (letter about him), 11 Feb 1917, 02 Apr 1917, 20 Mar 1919, 27 Apr 1920
    Buck, Mrs. Solon J.: 08 Mar 1942
    Burke, James Francis (Republican National Committee): undated
    Burkett, E. J. (Congressman): 21 Jan 1905
    Burroughs, Nannie H.: undated
    Burton, Theodore E. (Congressman, Ohio): 25 Feb 1927
    Burwell, J. Baldwin (Leader Publishing Co.): undated
    Butler?, Harold H. (Senator): 10 May 1944
    Butler, Hugh (Senator, Nebraska): 03 Apr 1944
    Byrd, Curley (President, U. of Maryland): 10 Jun 1944
    Byrd, Harry Flood (Senator, Virginia): undated, 10 Nov 1925, 27 Dec 1927 (letter about him), 17 Jun 1934, 23 May 1935, 26 Feb 1936, 25 Mar 1936, 27 Aug 1936, 10 Sep 1936, 08 Dec 1936, 19 May 1937, 07 Mar 1938, 16 Mar 1938, 05 Aug 1938, 06 Feb 1939, 18 Feb 1941, 09 Jun 1941, 16 Jun 1941, 26 Sep 1941, 02 Mar 1942, 09 Oct 1942, 29 Nov 1942, 28 Sep 1944, 28 Mar 1945, 24 May 1948, 25 May 1948, 11 Jun 1948, 07 Apr 1949, 22 Dec 1949, 02 Aug 1949, 19 Sep 1949, 21 Apr 1950
    Byrnes, James F. (Senator, South Carolina): 31 Jan 1938, 02 Jan 1939 (letter about him), 08 Jun 1940, Dec 1942, 11 Apr 1944, May 1944
    Cable, John L. (Congressman, Ohio): 14 Aug 1922
    Calder, William M. (Senator, New York): 16 Feb 1920
    Calderon, Madame Alvarez (Peruvian Legation): undated
    Camden, Johnson N. (Senator, Kentucky): 04 Mar 1915
    Campbell, L. H. (Major General): 25 Jan 1943
    Caniff, Milton (President, National Cartoonists Society): 13 May 1948, 14 Dec 1949
    Cannon, J. G. (Speaker of the House): 02 Dec 1910 (letter about him)
    Capehart, Charles (editor, The Cartoon): 06 Apr 1908 (C. Berryman drawing of Cannon)
    Capper, Arthur (Senator, Kansas): 13 Feb 1920, 06 Dec 1935
    Carlson, Frank (Congressman, Kansas): 02 Feb 1944
    Carnegie, Andrew: 14 May 1911 (letter from C. Berryman)
    Caughey, J. M. (cartoonist): 12 Nov 1915
    Chamberlain, George E. (Senator, Oregon): 11 Mar 1916
    Chamberlain, K. R. (cartoonist): 23 May 1914
    Chandler, Albert B. (Senator,Kentucky): 07 Jul 1942, 11 Aug 1942 (letter from his wife), 28 Jun 1943, 30 Mar 1944, 20 Apr 1944, 26 Apr 1945, 17 May 1945
    Chapple, Joe Mitchell (National Magazine, Boston): 31 Dec 1904
    Chiperfield, Burnett M. (Congressman, Illinois): 22 Apr 1916, 12 May 1916, 03 Jul 1929
    Choate, H. Lawrence: 09 Feb 1939
    Clapper, Raymond: 18 Jan 1939 (letter to Charles Dawes), 27 Jan 1939
    Clark, Champ (Speaker of the House): 29 Jun 1906
    Clark, P. L. (“Skippy” cartoonist): 25 Nov 1935
    Clay, Henry: 22 Apr 1829 (letter to Mark Hardin, Shelbyville Ky), 21 Jun 1843 (letter to a gentleman)
    Clements (Governor, Kentucky): 07 Jan 1948
    Coffeen, R. A. (cartoonist): 09 Dec 1940
    Colby, Bainbridge (Secretary of State): 01 Apr 1920
    Cole, Cyrenus (Congressman, Iowa): 01 Feb 1928, 10 Mar 1936
    Coleman, Harry (Pontiac Press Gazette): 12 Oct 1914
    Collier, William Miller (President, George Washington University): undated, 12 Jan 1921, 22 Mar 1921
    Connally, Tom (Senator, Texas): 06 Nov 1943
    Coolidge, Calvin: 03 Mar 1927, 01 Aug 1927 (letter about him)
    Cooper, Henry Allen (Congressman, Wisconsin): 14 Feb 1907, 24 Feb 1925
    Corby, William Stephen: undated calling card, 20 Oct 1916 (2), 14 Feb 1920 (2), 19 Jul 1926, 13 Aug 1932
    Cousins, A. G.? (cartoonist?): Dec 1904
    Cousins, Robert G. (Congressman): 02 Feb 1907
    Craig, Donald Alexander (author): 30 Sep 1924
    Crisp, Charles R. (Congressman, Georgia): 03 Oct 1932
    Culberson, C. A. (Senator, Texas): 07 Jul 1906
    Cummings, Homer S. (Attorney General): 29 Sep 1933 (letter about him), 30 Sep 1933, 21 May 1934, 28 Jun 1934 (letter from his wife), 02 Jul 1934, 22 Oct 1934, 12 Mar 1945
    Curran, Edward M. (U.S. Attorney, D.C.): 28 Oct 1946
    Cushman, Francis W. (Congressman): 25 Dec 1899, 05 Jan 1904
    Dale, Mrs. Thomas H. (Congressman's wife): 27 Apr 1906
    Daniel, J. (Senator): 23 Dec 1903 (illustrated letter)
    Daniels, Jonathan (son of Josephus Daniels): 15 Mar 1933, 29 Jan 1934, 16 Aug 1941
    Daniels, Josephus (Secretary of the Navy): undated calling card (from Mrs. Daniels), 25 Mar 1913, 15 May 1913 (letter about him), 25 Aug 1913 (letter about him), 31 Oct 1913, 26 Oct 1914, 12 Jan 1915, 22 Aug 1916, 08 Sep 1916, 27 Mar 1917, 22 Nov 1917, 27 Nov 1917, 24 Jan 1918, 12 Feb 1920, 29 Mar 1920, 03 Apr 1920, 20 Nov 1920 (3), 11 Jan 1921 (letter about him), 02 Mar 1921, 05 Jun 1926, 05 Apr 1927 (2), 04 Aug 1927, 10 Dec 1928, 15 Mar 1933, 19 May 1934, 11 May 1937, 19 Oct 1937, 18 Nov 1937, 25 Mar 1938, 18 May 1938, 09 Aug 1941
    Darling, Jay Norwood “Ding”: undated (letter about him), 19 Nov 1934
    Davies, Joseph E.: 09 Jun 1944, 16 Jun 1944
    Davis, James J. (Sec. of Labor and Senator, Pa.): Feb 9, 1923, 24 Dec 1925, 16 Feb 1931
    Davol, Ralph (Cosmos Club): 30 Mar 1920, 06 Apr 1925 (illustrated letter), 06 Apr 1930
    Dawes, Charles Gates (Vice President): 19 Jan 1928 (printed invitation), 24 Jan 1939 (letter to Clapper)
    Dawley, Mrs. M. Webster (League of Republican Women): 08 Feb 1938
    Debs, Eugene: 17 Aug 1912
    Delano, Frederic A. (Washington National Monument Society): 03 Feb 1944, 23 Feb 1944
    Delano, Victor: 06 May 1941 (on USS WEST VIRGINIA, Pearl Harbor), 25 Mar 1942 (on USS SAN JUAN)
    De Leon, T. C. (cartoonist?): 04 Aug 1904
    Denby, Edwin (Secretary of the Navy): 04 Mar 1922
    Depew, Chauncey: undated (2 printed invitations), 05 Jul 1923, 10 Feb 1926
    Dern, George H. (Secretary of War): 27 Jan 1935 (printed invitation)
    Dewey, Thomas E. (Governor, New York): 10 Oct 1944, 23 Jun 1947 (letter about him), 21 Nov 1947
    Dial, Nathaniel B. (Senator, S. C.): 17 Jan 1925
    Dickinson, L. J. (Congressman, Iowa): 09 Dec 1926
    Dillingham, William P. (Senator): 10 Mar 1904, 08 Mar 1916
    Dirksen, Everett M. (Congressman, Ill.): 09 Jun 1942
    Donahey, James Harrison (Plain Dealer): 02 Oct 1908, 30 Jan 1927
    Doughton, Robert L. (Congressman, N. C.): 10 Jan 1948
    Dowling, James J. (Democratic County Committee, N.Y.): 19 Dec 1934
    Downing, Robert L.: 19 Dec 1930, 05 Nov 1932
    Drewry, P. H. (Congressman, Virginia): 26 Feb 1935, 28 Mar 1935
    DuBois, James T. (State Department): undated, 26 Jan 1905, 26 Feb 1905, 06 Mar 1905, 24 Nov 1905, 22 Mar 1907, 18 Jul 1917
    Dugal, J. (Congressman): 19 Jan 1908
    Durkee, J. Stanley (President, Howard University): 11 May 1922, 24 May 1922, 03 Nov 1924, 24 Nov 1924
    Eccles, Marriner S. (Chairman, Federal Reserve System): 03 Oct 1941
    Edison, Thomas: 13 Aug 1914 (letter about him)
    Edwards, J. H. (Treasury Department): 18 Aug 1905
    Elliott, Richard (Asst. Comptroller General, GAO): 01 Dec 1932
    Ernst, Richard P. (Senator, Kentucky): 22 Dec 1922, 10 Nov 1925 (2), 15 Mar 1926, 19 Sep 1929, 15 Jun 1929
    Estopinal, Albert (Congressman, La.): 21 Mar 1914
    Evans, Silliman (Publisher, Chicago Sun): 14 Apr 1942
    Fall, Albert B. (Secretary of the Interior): 28 Feb 1923, 01 Mar 1923
    Farley, James A.: 20 Dec 1932, 03 Jan 1934, 30 Jan 1934 (letter about him), 11 May 1934, 21 May 1934, 13 Sep 1934, 18 Oct 1934, 26 Oct 1934, 04 Dec 1935, 28 Oct 1937, 10 Aug 1940, 16 Jan 1942, 01 Apr 1942, 03 Aug 1942, 13 Oct 1942, 12 Nov 1942, 26 Feb 1943, 11 Mar 1943, 06 Jul 1943, 17 Nov 1943, 29 Nov 1943, 29 Dec 1943, 03 Jan 1944, 27 Jan 1944, 29 Jan 1944, 05 May 1944, 21 Nov 1944
    Farnum Jno. (cartoonist): 03 Jun 1908
    Faulkner, Robert R. (attorney): 03 Jun 1935
    Fawcett, James Waldo (Washington Star): 02 Apr 1939
    Fenn, E. Hart (Congressman, Connecticut): 09 May 1929
    Fenning, F. A. (Inaugural Committee): 14 Jan 1925
    Fess, Simeon D. (Senator, Ohio): 19 Apr 1928 (letter about him), 28 Apr 1934
    Finch, Frank J. (cartoonist): 03 Feb 1905, 08 Apr 1910, 06 Jun 1910
    Fish, Hamilton, Jr. (Congressman, New York): 19 May 1936, 22 May 1936, 04 Jan 1937
    Fishback, Fred L. (Senator, Mass.): 26 Sep 1912
    Fisher, Walter L. (Sec. of the Interior): 25 Jan 1912
    Fitzgerald, Roy G. (Congressman, Ohio): 23 Feb 1925
    Foch, Le Marechal: Jun 1906
    Foley, E. H. (Asst. Sec. of the Treasury): 01 Nov 1947
    Foraker, Joseph B. (Senator, Ohio): 30 Aug 1905 (letter about him), 03 Sep 1905
    Frelinghuysen, J. S. (Senator, New Jersey): 04 Apr 1917 (letter about him)
    Galbraith, Alfred (Flint Daily Journal): 02 Jun 1907
    Gallinger, Jacob H. (Senator): 02 Feb 1905
    Gallivan, James A. (Congressman, Massachusetts): 05 Mar 1923
    Galloway, Ewing (news editor, Collier's): 07 Sep 1916
    Gard, Warren (Congressman, Ohio): 31 Mar 1916, 13 Feb 1917
    Gardner, A. P. (Congressman, Massachusetts): 09 Apr 1910 (letter about him), 26 Jan 1911, 31 Jan 1913, 28 Jun 1916, 20 Jul 1916
    Garfield, James Rudolph (Interior Dept.): 08 Nov 1907
    Garner, John Nance (Congressman, Texas): 16 Jan 1930, 15 Mar 1935
    Garrison, Lindley M. (Secretary of War): 19 Dec 1914, 25 Dec 1914, 11 Jan 1915, 28 Apr 1915, 30 Aug 1915
    Gerry, Peter G. (Senator): 06 May 1941
    Gerth, Arthur W. (President, American University): 02 May 1928
    Gibson, Charles D. (Division of Pictorial Publicity): 28 Dec 1917
    Gibson, Ernest W. (Congressman, Vermont): 19 Feb 1925
    Gilbert, Ralph (Congressman, Kentucky): 20 Oct 1921, 07 Jan 1922
    Gillett, Frederick H. (Senator, Massachusetts): 10 Feb 1928, 14 Feb 1928
    Gillette, Guy M. (Senator, Iowa): 05 Aug 1943
    Gittins, Robert H. (Congressman, N. Y.): 01 Aug 1914
    Glass, Carter (Secretary of the Treasury): 26 Jun 1903, 20 Jan 1919, 20 Jan 1919, 11 Feb 1920, 02 Dec 1929, 09 Nov 1936, 15 Mar 1937, 05 Apr 1937 (letter about him), 10 Apr 1937, 19 May 1937 (letter about him)
    Glover, Charles C. (Inaugural Committee): 09 Dec 1904, 21 Dec 1904, 20 Dec 1911
    Godwin, E. (Washington Times): 30 Dec 1918
    Goethals, General: undated (letter about him)
    Goff, “Roy”: Dec 1949
    Gore, Albert (Congressman, Tennessee): 25 May 1942
    Gorman, Arthur P. (Senator, Maryland): 03 Mar 1898, 28 Jan 1902, 07 Mar 1903, 02 May 1903, 28 Oct 1903 (letter from Mrs. Gorman)
    Grant, U.S., III: 15 Mar 1926, 22 Jun 1927, 03 Nov 1927, 20 Jun 1930
    Grayson, Cary T. (Inaugural Committee): 18 Feb 1933
    Green, Theodore Francis (Senator, R. I.): 17 Oct 1944
    [Gregory?], Tom (Attorney General): undated
    Grew, Joseph: 09 Apr 1943 (illustrated letter)
    Grey, Kenneth? (Dept. of the Treasury): 27 Mar 1945
    Grosvenor, Bert (National Geographic Society): 17 Mar 1940, 15 Apr 1940
    Grosvenor, Gilbert (National Geographic Society): 21 Mar 1921, 27 Apr 1921, 21 Dec 1921, 15 Nov 1927, 16 Nov 1931, 15 Mar 1935, 11 Nov 1935, 04 Nov 1938, 08 Nov 1944, 23 Dec 1949
    Guffey, Joseph F. (Senator, Pennsylvania): 16 Jun 1943, 29 Mar 1944
    Halleck, Charles A. (Congressman, Ind.): 02 Jan 1948
    Halsey, W. F. (Admiral): 24 Dec 1942
    Hamilton, Ernest? (Judge magazine): 19 Mar 1913
    Hamilton, Norman R. (Congressman, Virginia): 21 Jun 1938 (3), 22 Jun 1938 (2), 02 Jul 1938
    Hancock, Clarence E. (Congressman, N. Y.): 19 Apr 1941
    Hannegan, Robert E. (Democratic National Committee): 01 Mar 1945
    Harding, Warren G.: 06 Jan 1917, 11 May 1921 (printed invitation)
    Harriman, William Averill: 03 Jan 1939
    Harris, William J. (Senator, Georgia): 01 Nov 1913, 11 Feb 1920, 06 Apr 1920, 18 May 1920, 12 Dec 1922, 12 Jan 1923
    Harrison, William Henry: 13 Apr 1936
    Harvey, George (US Ambassador to England): 15 Oct 1914
    Hatch, Carl N. (Senator, New Mexico): 06 May 1937
    Hawley, Willis C. (Congressman, Oregon): 15 Mar 1929, 25 Mar 1930
    Hay, John (State Department): 31 Oct 1904, 02 Nov 1904
    Hays, Arthur: 27 Feb 1912
    Hays, Will H. (Postmaster General and President of the Motion Picture Producers & Distributors of America): 14 Jun 1921 (letter about him), 27 Jan 1922, 28 Feb 1922, 31 Aug 1922, 20 Dec 1922, 03 Mar 1937
    Heinl, Robert D.: 05 Feb 1912, 20 Mar 1913, 28 Jan 1915, 29 Jun 1920, 04 May 1938
    Hicks, Frederick C. (Congressman, New York): 19 Feb 1922, 01 Dec 1922, Nov 1923
    Hildreth, Melvin D. (Inaugural Committee): 28 Dec 1948
    Hilles, Charles D.: 23 Jul 1935
    Hitchcock, Ethan A. (Secretary of the Interior): 28 Jan 1908, 07 Mar 1916?
    Hitchcock, (Senator): undated, 10 Sep 1930 (letter about him)
    Hodges, John G.: undated
    Holt, Rush D. (Senator, West Virginia): 23 May 1935, 22 Nov 1937, 04 Aug 1940, 30 Aug 1940
    Hoover, Herbert: 03 Jan 1923 (letter from Hoover's secretary, Richard S. Emmet), 16 Aug 1949
    Hoover, J. (John) Edgar: 29 Aug 1933, 20 Oct 1934, 29 Oct 1934, 23 Mar 1936, 26 Mar 1936, 01 Oct 1936, 14 Apr 1937, 03 Feb 1942, 05 Feb 1942, 01 Jul 1942, 15 Jul 1942, 02 May 1944, 21 Jun 1949, 08 Jul 1949
    Hoover, Lou Henry: undated
    Hopkins, Harry L.: 10 Apr 1935, 24 Mar 1942
    Houston, David F. (Sec Treas): 12 Feb 1920